EARLY ADOPTER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER · CREATOR

🛛 +1 (551) 206-0263 | 🗷 afreay@villanova.edu | 🐔 www.anthonyfreay.com | 🖸 anthonyfreay | 🛅 anthonyfreay

## Summary \_

A software engineer who uses curiosity, drive, & modern technology to solve problems & improve technical skills. Recent internship experience at BNY Mellon has given exposure to how an application is designed, developed, & deployed within a wide-scale enterprise environment, as well as the importance of Test-Driven Development. Always ready to learn new technologies & continually grow by pursuing technical & non-technical challenges.

### **Education**

Villanova University (VU)

May 2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN <u>COMPUTER SCIENCE</u> & <u>PSYCHOLOGY</u> / CONCENTRATION IN <u>COGNITIVE SCIENCE</u>

Villanova, PA

Awards: O'Toole Presidential Scholar

Completed Courses: Data Structures & Algorithms I & II, Platform-Based Computing, Computer Systems I & II,

Discrete Structures, Statistics for Computer Science, Analysis of Algorithms

Current Courses: Theory of Computation, Information Visualization, Machine Learning

Skills \_

**Programming**Advanced: Java , JS/HTML/CSS

Intermediate: Golang, ReactJS, OpenAPI Spec {Swagger}

**Deployments** *Intermediate:* Containers {Docker}, Artifactory

DatabasesIntermediate: NoSQL {MongoDB}LanguagesEnglish (native), Spanish (fluent)

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Summer Technology Analyst Jersey City, NJ

• Overview: Given freedom to fully design, develop, & deploy a full-stack URL shortening service using Golang, ReactJS, MongoDB, Nginx, & Docker company-wide, reaching 35 countries and 52,000 employees

- Front-end: Minimally designed & developed using ReactJS, served with Nginx, & deployed in its own container using Docker
- **Back-end:** RESTful API developed using Golang, visually documented using Swagger.io, URLs mapped & stored using MongoDB, & deployed in its own container using Docker

# Leadership & Volunteering \_\_\_\_\_

VU Rays of Sunshine Sep. 2017 - Present

MATHEMATICS TUTOR Villanova, PA

• Weekly tutor groups of ~3 under-represented minority middle school students dealing with behavioral challenges at Northern Children's Services

VU Tech Crew Aug. 2017 - Present

Senior Staff Member Villanova, PA

Assist in the production & facilitation of various events (20+ to date), such as Commencement (~7500 attendees)
 & Orientation (~2500 attendees)

#### VU ACLAMO (Accion Comunal Latinoamericana de Montgomery County)

Aug. 2017 - May 2018

Volunteer Villanova, PA

• Led a weekly tutoring session for 15 Spanish-speaking 5th grade students, focusing on mathematics, reading comprehension, & homework translation

# **Projects** \_

simple-url Recreating & optimizing BNY project, will then integrate & substitute different databases & front-end technologies personal-site

Designed, developed, & deployed personal-site to refine web development skills & improve digital presence